我们现在是要找
Now we're looking for two binomials
两个相乘得出给定三项式的二项式
that multiply to get the given trinomial.
每当我得不到智力上的挑战时
Whenever I wasn't being challenged intellectually,
我的大脑总是十分乐意来满足我的需要
my brain was more than happy to step up and accommodate.
仿佛就是在我头骨里的完美玩伴
It was like having the perfect playmate in my skull.
长官  宇宙背景探测者卫星开始不受控旋转了
Sir, the COBE satellite is going into an uncontrolled spin.
解决问题啊
So fix it!
解决不了  我们的电脑程序并没有被设计来
We can't. Our computer programs weren't designed
处理混乱的系统
to handle a chaotic system.
可恶  如果有人能算出该如何调转
Darn it! If only someone could calculate the maneuver
让它重新稳定下来就行了
and make it stable again!
的确有人
There is someone.
那就是我
And it's me.
你只是个孩子
You're just a kid.
一个知道如何加入一个X立方数
A kid who knows to add an x-cubed term
进简单的谐波振荡器的人
to a simple harmonic oscillator.
如果你把太阳能板展开一米
If you extend the solar panel by one meter,
你就能救下这人造卫星
you'll save your satellite.
听到他说的了吧  快做
You heard him. Do it!
谢尔顿
Sheldon?
你有听进我说的任何一句话吗
Were you paying attention to anything I said?
有啊
Yes.
那我说了什么
Then what'd I say?
当要因式分解一个三项式时
When factoring a trinomial
如果首项系数不是1
where the leading coefficient isn't one,
必需得以递减顺序
it must be written in descending order
从最高幂写到最低幂
from highest power to lowest power.
好吧  你说对了
Well... yeah.
你就能救下这人造卫星
You'll save your satellite.
听到他说的了吧  快做
You heard him. Do it!
成功了  人造卫星稳定下来了
It worked. The satellite is stable!
太好了
Yes!
谢了  孩子
Thanks, kid.
你救了我一条汪命
You really saved my bottom.
跟你的汪命说"不客气"
Tell your bottom, "It's welcome."
♪ 世上没人比我强壮 ♪
♪ Nobody else is stronger than I am ♪
♪ 昨天我移了一座山 ♪
♪ Yesterday I moved a mountain ♪
♪ 我相信我能当你的英雄 ♪
♪ I bet I could be your hero ♪
♪ 我是个了不起的小家伙 ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man ♪
少
年
谢尔顿
保佑我们的食欲  身体与灵魂
And bless our appetites, both physical and spiritual,
我们尊崇您
to honor You in all we do.
以耶稣之名
In Jesus' name.
以前的"保佑准备这餐点的人"那套呢
What happened to "Bless the hands that prepared it"?
我觉得可以轮着说
I thought I'd mix it up.
我喜欢旧的那套
I miss the old one.
我也是
Me, too.
是啊  我喜欢原来那套的原因是...
Yeah, what I like about the other one...
也保佑准备这餐点的人
And bless the hands that prepared it.
-阿门  -阿门
- Amen. - Amen.
大家今天好吗
So, how was everybody's day?
我受够高中了
I'm done with high school.
你这是什么意思
What does that mean?
在高中我也学不到东西
Well, I don't learn anything there,
我也不想去上了
and I don't want to go anymore.
那你想上哪去呢
Well, where do you think you're gonna go?
随便啦  他想去哪去哪
Who cares? Let him go.
嘘  你说
Shh. Well?
我跟约翰·斯特吉斯博士一直有通信
I've been corresponding with Dr. John Sturgis
他在东德克萨斯理工大学教书
at East Texas Tech.
他说我能去旁听他的课
He said I could audit his course.
你跟陌生人当笔友吗  这样好吗
You're pen pals with a stranger? Is this okay?
他不是陌生人  他是知名科学家
He's not a stranger. He's a famous scientist.
他用碳測年法探出了最古老的人类粪便
He carbon-dated the oldest human feces.
这可一点都不奇怪
That ain't strange.
谢利  我很高兴你有这份求知的心
Now, Shelly, I appreciate that you want to expand your horizons,
但你怎么去那学校啊
but how would you even get there?
那学校离这里要一个小时车程
The school's an hour away.
我要工作  你爸爸也要工作
I'm working, your dad's working.
再说一次  随便他吧  让他去
Again, who cares? Let him go.
他可以路上搭便车
He could hitchhike.
完美
Perfect.
每周一次而已
It's only one day a week,
我本来希望姥姥能载我去
and I was hoping Meemaw could take me.
我要开始在自己家吃晚饭了
I'm gonna start eating dinner at my house.
你以后最好赚大钱
You better make a whole lot of money
在我老了以后好好照顾我
and take care of me when I'm old.
我对金钱没兴趣
I'm not interested in money.
我有兴趣的是追求知识
I'm interested in the pursuit of knowledge.
你这话说给一个
That is the wrong thing to say to someone
牺牲周五夜来当你司机的人真是大错特错
who is spending her Friday night as your chauffeur.
你知道司机这个词起源于法语的"司炉工"吗
Did you know the word chauffeur is French for "stoker,"
因为最早的汽车是用蒸汽动力
because the first automobiles were steam-powered,
而驾驶员得给引擎烧锅炉
and the driver had to stoke the engine?
你看看  我为什么要费心力载你去大学呢
Right there. Why am I driving you to college
你明明已经什么都懂了
when you already know everything?
我才没有什么都懂
I didn't know everything,
但跟姥姥那些玩水中有氧的朋友相比
but compared to her friends at water aerobics,
她会有这种感觉也不意外
I could see how it felt that way.
你的教室到了
Okay, this is you.
祝你好运
Good luck.
你不打算陪我进去  把我安排妥当吗
Aren't you going to walk me in and get me situated?
是的  当然
Oh, yes, of course.
这边请  王子殿下
Right this way, my prince.
他们为什么都要看我们
Why are they all looking at us?
我觉得他们是在看你
I think they're looking at you.
大家好
Oh. Hello.
来坐下吧
There you go.
一切都妥当了吗
Okay, you all situated?
是的  应该都好了
I believe so, yes.
我就在教室外等
I'll be right outside.
你确定你不想留下来
Are you sure you don't want to stay
一起学习量子色动力学吗
and learn about quantum chromodynamics?
破坏回家一路上你给我讲个不停的乐趣吗
And spoil the fun of you telling me all about it on the ride home?
那怎么可以
No way.
你真聪明
Smart.
那是我姥姥
That's my meemaw.
-他真的是我们的吗  -谢谢
- He's really ours? - Thank you.
电影《洛奇2》
别这样  辛苦的人是你
Oh, come on, you done all the work.
艾黛丽安  我真不敢相信你做到这一切
Adrian, I can't believe you done this.
你能帮帮我吗
Can you help me?
帮什么
With what?
我作业不会写
I don't understand my homework.
你问我干嘛
You're asking me?
我连自己的作业都搞不懂了
I don't understand my own homework.
我知道啊  但我没别人能问了
I know, but you're all I got.
这是什么作业
What kind of homework is it?
语法
Grammar.
我的语法也不好
I ain't great with grammar.
语法就是说话  我们两个说话都挺好啊
Well, grammar's just talking, and we both talk good.
大概吧  给我看看
I guess. Gimme.
下列的句子中  你得判断出
There's a list of sentences, and you're supposed to say
哪句是完整的句子
if each one's a complete sentence or not.
第一句是
The first one is,
"我国大多数人"
"Most people in the country""
这感觉不像是个句子啊
That doesn't sound like a sentence.
但你问问我什么人开小货车
But ask me who drives pickup trucks.
什么人开小货车
Who drives pickup trucks?
我国大多数人
Most people in the country.
现在听起来像完整句子了
Well, now it does sound like one.
我跟你说了吧  很容易混乱
I told you, it's confusing.
我帮不了你
I can't help you.
你觉得我们两个笨吗
Do you think we're stupid?
谢尔顿现在都在大学听课了
Sheldon's in college right now,
而我们两个都弄不明白你的作业
and we can't figure out your homework.
你觉得呢
What do you think?
有时候我都告诉我自己
Sometimes I tell myself I only look stupid
是因为他太聪明我才显笨
because he's so smart.
把书给我
Give me the book.
别在这干坐着啊  去给我做三明治啊
Don't just sit there, make me a sandwich.
马上来
Coming up.
-你好  -你好
- Hello. - ‭Hello.
抱歉打扰了  但你那个纹路是双重篮状编织吗
Forgive me, but is that pattern a double basket weave?
大概是吧
Um, I suppose so.
我都叫它"圈圈圆圆圈圈"
I've always just called it a "Loop-loop whoopsie-do."
真的很厉害了
Well, it's very impressive.
你编织吗
Do you knit?
没有  但我一直觉得很有意思
No, but it's always intrigued me.
你可能不信
Believe it or not,
但世界上的第一台计算机就是织布机啊
the first computer was a loom.
真的吗
Is that so?
是的
It is.
那好吧
Well, okay.
好的
Okay.
抱歉失陪啦
Well, if you'll excuse me, uh,
我得去教课了
I have a class to teach.
想必你就是我孙子的笔友
Oh, you must be my grandson's pen pal.
什么
I'm sorry?
谢尔顿·库珀
Sheldon Cooper.
九岁就写得一手完美好字的孩子
The nine-year-old with the flawless penmanship.
我很期待跟他见面呢
I look forward to meeting him.
他就在里面  你绝对会发现他
Well, he's right in there. You can't miss him.
他就这么点大
He's about yea big. ‭Oh.
你会一起来上课吗
An-An-And will you be joining us?
你课上要说量子色动力学吗
Will you be discussing quantum chromodynamics?
我想会的
I certainly hope so.
-那我想我不去了  -你确定吗
- Then I don't think so. - Are you sure?
每天都是学习新东西的好日子
Every day is a chance to learn something new.
我能问问题吗
Can I ask questions?
不问怎么学会呢
Well, how else can you learn?
那就来吧
Well, let's do it, then.
我叫约翰
My name's John.
我叫康妮
And I'm Connie.
我的中间名是惠特尼
My middle name's Whitney.
现在我知道啦
And now I know that.
我很高兴你喜欢这个课
Well, I'm so glad you enjoyed it.
谢尔顿  你对你的第一堂
So, Sheldon, what did you think
理论物理学课有何想法
of your first theoretical physics class?
我想我这一辈子都要在这领域
I think I'm gonna do this for the rest of my life.
好选择
Good choice.
康妮  我很希望能再跟你见面
Connie, I would like to see you again.
或许有机会我们可以一起吃个晚饭
Perhaps we could have dinner sometime.
太好了  我们很愿意
Yes, we would love that.
我们会愿意吗
We would?
我们会不愿意吗
We wouldn't?
你会不愿意吗
You wouldn't?
我们愿意
We would.
妙哉
Excellent.
妙哉  那我们上哪吃
Excellent. So, where are we eating?
好  这里写"完整的句子
Okay, this says "A complete sentence
永远会包含有动词"
always contains a verb."
哪个是动词
Which one's a verb?
"动词指描述一个动作的词
"A verb is a word that describes an action.
我玩西洋跳棋  你吃意大利面"
I play checkers. You eat spaghetti."
我俩作业烂透了
We suck at homework.
动作是烂透了
The action is sucking.
你作业上的第一题是
So, the first one on your homework is,
"我国大多数人"
"Most people in the country."
我没看到有动作词啊
I don't see an action word.
我也没看到
Neither do I.
小乔治  我觉得这不是完整句子
Georgie, I don't think this is a sentence.
我觉得你说得对
I think you're right.
我们现在得把它改好
Now I just have to fix it.
往里面加个动词吧  小姑娘
Put a verb in there, girl.
我觉得你可能有点想太多了
I think you might be getting a little ahead of yourself.
我可不认为  他们绝对是相爱了
I don't think so. They're in love.
他们那时候看着对方的眼睛
They were looking into each other's eyes
仿佛对方眼中有着
like there was something in there
除了角膜跟虹膜以外的东西
other than corneas and irises.
如果真是这样  那也非常好啊
Well, if that's the case, that'd be wonderful.
这何止是非常好
It'd be more than wonderful.
如果他们结婚了  我们家族的聪明人数量
If they get married, we immediately double
就可以瞬间加倍呢
the number of smart people in our family.
意思就是从一个变两个
That means we go from one to two.
不用你解释
I got that.
所以你有听懂任何一部分吗
So, did you understand any of it?
一个字都没听懂
Not a word. ‭
不过他穿着花呢夹克衫  还有肘部贴布
But he had on a tweed jacket with the elbow patches,
一看就是很懂自己在说什么的人啦
so he must know what he's talking about.
妈呀  谢尔顿可兴奋了
Boy, Sheldon's fired up.
他爱死了
Oh, he loved it.
他坐在那听了一个半小时的课
He sat there for an hour and a half
快乐得像在泥里打滚的小猪一样
just as happy as a pig in poop.
他还提到了你陪他去上课
He mentioned you were pretty happy
也玩得挺开心的啊
about the whole experience, too.
我想老巫师先生
Well, I guess Mr. Wizard did take
对我也挺青睐有加
a bit of a shine to me.
什么意思
What's that mean?
意思是他约我出去吃晚餐
It means he asked me out to dinner.
没什么大不了
No big deal.
你要去吗
So, you going?
你什么时候见过我拒绝免费的晚餐
When have you known me to turn down a free meal?
这倒是真的
Ain't that the truth.
你这面团胖宝宝也好意思说我
Says the Pillsbury Doughboy.
这倒是真的
Ain't that the truth.
我也是会受伤的好吗
I do have feelings, y'all.
那个别涂太多了
Don't put on too much of that.
我们希望他喜欢的是你的头脑
We want him to like you for your mind.
我想在男人领域  我知道自己在做什么
I think I know what I'm doing when it comes to men.
如果是真的  那你为什么一个人住
If that's true, then why do you live alone?
因为我丈夫死了  还有别的问题吗
Because my husband died. Any other questions?
他到了
He's here!
我去开门
I'll get it.
好像真的涂太多了
Maybe that is a bit much.
你好  斯特吉斯博士
Hello, Dr. Sturgis.
你好  谢尔顿
Hello, Sheldon.
请进  姥姥正在楼上为约会打扮
Come in. Meemaw's upstairs getting ready for your date.
太棒了
Wonderful.
你们家真温馨
Oh, my, this is a lovely house.
可不是嘛  你能想象你住在这里吗
Isn't it? Can you see yourself living here?
我就能
I can.
以下信息对你追求姥姥应该有帮助
Here are some things you might find helpful about Meemaw.
她最喜欢的颜色是紫色
Her favorite color is purple,
她最喜欢的冰淇淋是薄荷巧克力口味
her favorite ice cream: mint chip,
她最喜欢吃的是墨西哥菜
and her favorite food is Mexican.
妙哉  很有用
Excellent. Good to know.
她喜欢赌博  打保龄球  尤其喜欢我
She loves gambling, bowling, and especially me.
你聊我聊再多都不为过
You can't talk enough about me.
告诉我更多你的事
Tell me more about you.
我最喜欢的颜色是蓝色
My favorite color is blue.
我也是
Mine, too.
-我最喜欢的冰淇淋是香草口味  -很棒
- My favorite ice cream: vanilla. - Good man.
我最喜欢的食物是意粉配热狗丁
My favorite food: spaghetti with hot dogs cut up in it.
我从来没吃过
I've never had that.
你最喜欢的食物是什么
What's your favorite food?
烤奶酪三明治
Grilled cheese.
吃这个很容易烫到嘴巴怎么办
What about the risk of mouth burn?
那就是吃香草冰淇淋的绝佳借口
It's a perfect excuse for vanilla ice cream.
如果你今晚想求婚  我会祝福你
If you want to propose tonight, you have my blessing.
帅哥们好呀
Hello, boys.
康妮  你好
Hello, Connie.
这是给你的
These are for you.
谢谢  这花真美
Aw, thank you. They're beautiful.
其中有几朵是紫色的呢
Some of them are purple.
的确是呢
So they are.
我去把花插到水里吧
I should probably get 'em into some water.
我来
I can do that.
你们俩开始求爱吧
You two begin your courtship.
-小饼饼  -什么事
- Moonpie. ‭- Yes?
回家去
Go home.
这样你们就可以开始求爱了  明白
So you can begin the courtship, got it.
快走
Go!
斯特吉斯博士
Dr. Sturgis,
我想让你知道  我高兴得不得了
I just want you to know I couldn't be more pleased.
我去把花放好
‭Well, let me take care of these,
然后我们就出发
and then we'll head out.
我需要借你电话叫辆计程车
I just need to borrow your phone to call a cab.
为什么
Why?
我不开车
I don't drive.
那你怎么来的
Well, how did you get here?
我骑我的自行车来的
I rode my bicycle.
你骑你的自行车吗
You rode your bicycle?
我有一辆施文牌变速自行车
I have a Schwinn Speedster.
有三个变速档  但我只用一个
It's got three gears. I only use one.
这样吧  不如我们开我的车
I tell you what, how about we take my car?
妙哉
Excellent.
你介意我坐在后座吗
So, would you be opposed to me sitting in the back seat?
据统计  那是车上最安全的位子
It's statistically the safest part of the car.
其实我介意
Actually, I would.
有问有答
Asked and answered.
乔治收
米希·库珀  一百分
你看到之后哭了吗
Did you cry when you saw it?
才没有
No.
为什么不哭
Why not?
因为这没什么大不了
'Cause it ain't that big a deal.
好吧
Okay.
你把考卷挂墙上了吗
Did you hang it on your wall?
滚开
Get out of here!
我要告诉大家你哭了
I'm telling people you cried.
你喜欢鳄梨酱吗
Do you like guacamole?
我不知道
I don't know.
我们缅因州那边的墨西哥菜不多
Being from Maine, we didn't have much Mexican food.
墨西哥人也不多  人其实也不多
Or Mexican people. Or people.
就是捣碎的鳄梨  你应该会喜欢
It's just mashed up avocados. I think you'd like it.
而且他们就在餐桌上捣碎
And they do it right here at the table.
是厨房里没地方了吗
Did they run out of room in the kitchen?
不是啦  是类似表演
No, it's-it's like, you know, a show.
-像红花铁板烧餐厅一样  -没错
- Like Benihana. - ‭Exactly.
该餐厅在烹饪过程中会穿插表演
我不喜欢红花餐厅
I don't like Benihana.
-我们还是别吃鳄梨酱了  -不
- Let's skip the guacamole. ‭- No, no.
你喜欢  而我希望这场约会
You like it, and I want this date
能够让你喜欢  所以点吧
to be appealing to you, so let's order it.
好吧
Okay.
我可能会喜欢  也可能不喜欢
I might enjoy it. I might not.
但我愿意赌一把
But, uh, I'm willing to take that gamble.
我听说你也喜欢赌一把
Which, uh, I'm given to understand you also like.
那小叛徒全都告诉你了是不是
Oh, that little rat just told you everything, didn't he?
别不好意思  我偶尔也喜欢小赌一把
Don't feel bad, I enjoy a little gambling now and then.
真的吗
Do you?
你开车时我坐在危险的副驾了  不是吗
I sat in your front seat, didn't I?
很好  我逗你笑了
Good, I made you laugh.
老实说  我刚不是想搞笑
Full disclosure, I wasn't trying to be funny.
这也不是笑话
Still not trying.
他们一时半会还不会回来
They're not gonna be back for a while.
上床去吧
Go to bed.
我睡不着的
I won't be able to sleep.
我没叫你去睡觉
I'm not telling you to go to sleep,
我是叫你上床去
I'm telling you to go to bed.
你觉得他们今晚会不会发生关系
You don't think they'll have relations tonight, do you?
现在我要叫你去睡觉了
Now I'm telling you to go to sleep.
约翰  你结过婚吗
So, John, you ever been married?
没有
No.
爱过吗
Ever been in love?
七次
Seven times.
七次啊
Seven times?
那你怎么没成过家
How come you never settled down?
我的感情没得到回应
Well, my feelings were not reciprocated.
真让人难过
Well, that's so sad.
她们可不觉得难过
Not for them.
她们似乎都对结局很满意
They all seemed pleased with the outcome.
特别是四号
Especially number four.
她说自己逃过一劫
She said she dodged a bullet.
第一次约会说这个  很勇敢
That is a very brave thing to say on a first date.
为什么
Why?
如果还有第二次约会  我再告诉你
If there's a second date, I'll tell you.
我有机会约你第二次吗
I have a chance at a second date?
这进展真顺利
This is going very well.
尝尝鳄梨酱
Try the guacamole.
不不  用玉米片蘸着吃
No, no, no. With a chip.
好吧
Okay.
这样吃
Like this.
这就对了
There you go.
那墨西哥炸卷饼又是怎么个吃法
Now, how do chimichangas work?
我不知道
I have no idea.
我们应该试试  看有什么名堂
Well, I think we should try and find out.
进行得怎么样
How'd it go?
搞什么
Oh! What the hell?
我想知道你约会得怎么样
I wanted to know how your date went,
我看你睡觉看腻了
and I got bored watching you sleep.
你在这多久了
How long have you been there?
67分钟
67 minutes.
快点一五一十告诉我
Now, tell me everything.
走开  让我睡觉
Go away. Let me sleep.
好吧
Okay.
不过在我走之前  我该担心
But before I go, should I be worried
他没在你床上吗
he's not in your bed?
滚出去
Get out!
我真心希望你对他的态度比对我好
I certainly hope you were nicer to him.
出去
Out!
你还会再见他吗
So, are you gonna see him again?
我说不好
I don't know.
他骑车来我家的
He showed up at my house on a bike.
哈雷机车吗
Like a Harley?
是施文自行车
Like a Schwinn.
脚踩的自行车那种车吗
You mean a bike bike?
手把上有个铃铛那种标准自行车
With a jingle bell on the handlebar and everything.
还挺可爱的
Well, that's kind of charming.
他不会开车
He doesn't know how to drive a car.
也不想知道怎么开
Doesn't want to know.
好吧  没那么可爱了
Okay, a little less charming.
他有种特质
There's something about him.
他很聪明  又温柔有趣
I mean, he's smart as hell, and gentle and funny.
未必是故意搞笑  但还是很有趣
Not always on purpose, but he's funny.
我从没见过他这样的人
I never met anybody like him.
听起来像谢尔顿
Sounds like Sheldon.
你为什么要
Now, why would you go
把这念头灌输到我脑子里
and put that thought in my mind?
我认为你该再给他一次机会
Well, I think you should give him another try.
我同意妈妈的话
I agree with Mom.
谢尔顿
Sheldon!
不是吧
Oh, no.
我昨晚过得很开心
很希望能再见到你
约翰·斯特吉斯
现在我们可以讨论
So, now we can discuss
微扰量子色动力学修正对半径矢量轴是什么
what the perturbative QCD corrections to R-bar look like.
你还可以把它写成
So, you can also write it as "R"
用"R"除以半径长度"R"
divided by the length of "R."
就会得出单位长度...
That would be a vector
的矢量
of unit length...
与半径"R"...
...parallel...
平行
to "R."
抱歉  我刚说到哪了
I'm sorry, where was I?
用"R"除以半径长度"R"
"R" Divided by the length of "R."
那会是单位长度的矢量  与半径"R"平行
That would be a vector of unit length parallel to "R."
对  谢谢你
Oh, yes. Thank you.
所以如果用"R"除以半径长度"R"
So, if you divide "R" by the length of "R,"
就会得出单位长度...
that would be a vector...
的矢量  与...
of unit length parallel...
平行...
to...
我想你最好先出去
I think you need to leave.
那么
So...
当我们用"R"除以半径长度"R"
when we divide "R" By the length of "R,"
就会得出单位长度的矢量
that would be a vector of unit length
与半径"R"平行
parallel to "R."
长官  坏消息
Sir, bad news.
别告诉我又出现了一个
Don't tell me. There's another problem
我们不够聪明来解决的问题
we're not smart enough to solve?
是人造卫星  液氦快汽化了
It's the satellite-- the liquid helium is boiling off.
怎么会发生这种事
Well, why the heck would that happen?
我来告诉你
I'll tell you why.
太阳一定是被太阳能板反射
The sun must be glinting off the solar panel
照到杜瓦瓶了
and hitting the dewar.
你为什么不知道这点
Why didn't you know that?
我就是个废物  长官
I'm a disappointment, sir.
我们必须计算出所有
We need to calculate all the Euler angles
会导致太阳照到液氦的欧拉角
that would cause the sun to hit the liquid helium.
你能及时算出来吗
Can you do it in time?
跟我的新朋友约翰·斯特吉斯一起  我就可以
I can with my new friend, Dr. John Sturgis.
大家好
Hello.
你好
Hi.
他准备跟我姥姥结婚
He's gonna marry my meemaw.
我给她买了一辆自行车
I bought her a bicycle.
是紫色的自行车
A purple bicycle.
紫色  感觉是真爱啊
Purple? Sounds like love to me.
库珀先生
Mr. Cooper?!
你有专心听吗
Are you paying attention?
这些我已经会了
I already know this.
你已经会了吗
You know this?
但他们不会  所以请继续吧
But they don't, so by all means, continue.